嘿 你想听几首我重新填词
Hey, would you like to hear some songs
想激起孩子们对自然理论科学的兴趣的歌吗?
I've rewritten to get children interested in the hard sciences?
- 好啊  - 你没开玩笑?
- Sure.  - Really?
当然 我喜欢音乐 也喜欢科学
Yeah. Well, I like music, I like science,
更喜欢嘲笑Sheldon 唱吧
I like making fun of Sheldon. Hit it.
# 有个科学家 提出了理论 #
# There was a scientist who had a theory #
# 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦 #
# And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o #
英国物理学家 数学家
# 詹-姆-斯 #
# J-A-M-E-S #
# 克-拉-克 #
# C-L-E-R-K #
# 空格 麦-克-斯-韦 #
# Space M-A-X-W-E-L-L #
# 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦 #
# And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o #
# 有个科学家 提出了理论 #
# There was a scientist who had a theory #
# 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦 #
# And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o #
# 詹-姆-斯 #
# J-A-M-E-S #
好了 好了 我们... 懂了
Uh, okay, okay. Uh, we... we get it.
也许你们会喜欢这首
Perhaps you'd prefer this one.
# 可爱的蜘蛛 不是一只昆虫 #
# The itsy bitsy spider is not an insect at all #
# 因为它有八条腿 #
# Because it has eight legs #
# 两部分身体 #
# And two body parts #
- 真的很不错 Sheldon  - 谢谢
- That's pretty cool, Sheldon.  - Thank you.
你们认不认识碧昂斯?
Do either of you know Beyonce?
我想让她来唱这些歌
I'd love her to get behind it.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿  - 嘿 你好
- Hey.  - Hey. Hello.
你们知道国家航空航天局正在进行的
You guys know the new Discovery class missions
- 发现计划任务吗?  - 知道
- that NASA's been working on?  - Yeah.
他们想要加入一条"来自地球的信息"
Well, they're looking to include a message from Earth
万一能遇上外星生物呢
in case one of them is encountered by alien life.
哦
Oh.
我以前遇到外星生物的时候... 发现
When I encountered alien life, I... I discovered
关键是不能抢它的专座
that the key thing was not to sit in its spot.
Leonard有哮喘
好吧 没有滤气器 你难以呼吸我们的空气
All right, you can't breathe our air without an inhaler,
他对地球坚果过敏
he's allergic to Earth nuts,
但我才是外星人
but I'm the alien.
反正
Anyway,
他们要求包括我在内的
I'm among a handful of scientists
几位科学家 上交一份信息内容
that have been asked to submit a design proposal
和传送系统的设计提案
for the message and its delivery system.
- 太棒了  - 恭喜 真为你高兴
- Excellent.  - Congratulations. Good for you.
我在想你们有没有兴趣
And I was wondering if any of you guys
来帮我一起做
would like to help me do it.
开什么玩笑? 当然愿意 你有什么想法?
Are you kidding? Yes. What did you have in mind?
我告诉你该做什么: 放弃人类
I'll tell you exactly what you should do: avoid the presumption
- 感知模式的设想  - 当然可以
- of the Terran sensory input paradigm.  - Yeah, absolutely.
你需要设计一个可以传递信息
You need a device capable of delivering information
给各种感知模式的设备
across a wide range of perceptual modalities.
任何有智慧的有机体都至少会拥有
Any intelligent organism would at the very least need
在空间中确认物体位置的能力
the ability to locate the position of objects in space.
所以理想的星际通用语言应该是触觉
So the ideal interstellar lingua franca would be haptic.
一台可以跨感官传送信息的
Ooh, how about a 3-D tactile communicator rigged
3D触觉交流仪怎么样?
for cross-sensory transposition?
我早就料到了
Exactly what I expected.
两个人把想法强加于我
Two people forcing their ideas on me
只有一位绅士愿意问问
and only one gentleman who could be bothered
我有什么想法
to ask me what my thoughts were.
- 你们俩淘汰了  - 恭喜 Leonard
- You two are out.  - Congratulations, Leonard,
你入选小组了
you're on the team.
我妈妈教出了个绅士
My mommy raised a gentleman.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季第21集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥得了抑郁症
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理
翻译: 糖醋影 蚝油薇 麻辣酥
嘿 谢谢你特地过来
Hey. Thanks for coming by.
不客气 我很乐意帮忙
Yeah. I'm excited to help.
我很想叫上他们俩 可是...
I would have included the others, but...
你很清楚会变成什么状况
you know exactly what would've happened.
他们会把项目抢过去 指使我们跑腿
They would've taken over the project and bossed us around.
我明白
I get it.
就今天早上 Sheldon不让我往提子脆麦片里
Uh, just this morning, Sheldon wouldn't let me put almond milk
加杏仁牛奶 因为他说
on my Grape-Nuts because he said
理论上讲两种坚果会冲突
it was a theoretical nut conflict.
你应该让他别多管闲事
You should have told him to mind his own business.
没错 总比我今天早上说的那句强
Yeah. That's better than what I did say, which was,
"好吧 我就加苏打水得了"
"Fine, I'll eat them with club soda."
他们凭什么觉得自己能管所有事情?
What makes them think they're always in charge of everything?
他们是大哥
Mmm, they're alpha males.
那我们算什么?
What does that make us?
我们也许是二哥 就是二把手
We could be betas. They're second in charge.
好吧 听上去不错
Okay, that sounds good.
或许我们是小弟
Or we could be omegas.
他们会被大哥和二哥呼来喝去
They get pushed around by the alphas and the betas.
好吧 听上去就是我们的状况
Okay, that sounds like us.
无所谓了 这里没大哥
Whatever. There's no alphas here,
这是你的项目
and this is your project.
你是管事的 想怎么开工?
You're in charge. How do you want to start?
我不知道 你想怎么开工?
I don't know. How do you want to start?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们应该打电话给Sheldon和Howard吗?
Should we call Sheldon and Howard?
不 我们靠自己可以做到
No. We can do this by ourselves.
嗯 很好 你想怎么开工?
Okay. Great. How do you want to start?
我不知道 你想怎么开工?
I don't know. How do you want to start?
Sheldon开门 Sheldon开门
Sheldon. Sheldon.
Sheldon开门
Sheldon.
我猜你一开始是打算开个玩笑
I bet that started off as a joke,
但叫到第三遍的时候
but by the third one you realized
你发现自己神奇般的很享受这过程
there was something strangely enjoyable about it.
对 我有点想再来一次
Yeah, I kind of want to do it again.
我不推荐 你今后会这样敲门一辈子的
I don't recommend it. You'll be doing it the rest of your life.
如果你来找Leonard 他在Koothrappali家
Anyway, if you're looking for Leonard, he's with Koothrappali.
不 其实我是来找你谈谈的
Uh, no, I actually came to talk to you.
真不错
How nice.
以下是我感兴趣的话题:
Here are some topics that interest me:
- 量子力学 火车 旗子...  - 不 不是
- quantum mechanics, trains, flags...  - No, no.
- 我是想谈谈我的演艺事业  - 抱歉
- It's about my acting career.  - Oh, sorry.
此话题不在清单里
That's not on the list.
- 那...  - 等等 不对
- Well...  - Oh, wait. No.
要不我们先
How about we split
撇开差异 谈谈为什么奥地利
the difference and discuss why Austria
是个大公国 而非传统的公爵领地
was an archduchy and not just a regular duchy.
好吧 听着 事情是这样的 我很喜欢医药销售...
Okay, look, here's the thing. I like pharmaceutical sales...
工作也很顺利... 但我有个电影试镜
it's going great... but I have an audition for a movie,
如果我选上了 可能会搞砸一切
and if I get it, it could screw everything up.
嗯 我知道你该做什么了
Hmm. I know exactly what you should do.
不幸的是 我不能告诉你
Unfortunately, I cannot tell you.
为什么?
Well, why?
我想要重新开始
I'm attempting to turn over a new leaf.
今天早些时候 有人向我指出
Earlier today, it was pointed out to me
我总想把想法强加于人
that I tend to force my ideas on people.
你真的不打算告诉我?
You're really not gonna tell me?
不 时机已经过了
No, that train has left the station.
听着 我们可以
Now, we can play this
用两种方法解决
one of two ways.
你可以说"火车火车 告诉我"
You can say, "Trains, tell me more,"
或者...
or...
你可以一直那么看着我
you can just look at me like that
我就会说了
and I'll start.
你在做什么?
What's going on in here?
我在做分子鸡尾酒
I am making molecular cocktails.
这个小球其实是杯"大都会"
This sphere is actually a cosmopolitan.
哦
Oh.
那要怎么喝?
How do you drink it?
直接放进嘴里 噗嗤一下含碎就行了
Oh, just put it in your mouth and pop it like a zit.
我想我还是喝啤酒好了
I think I'll have a beer.
先和我拍张照片
First take a picture with me.
为什么?
Why?
我和Raj一直说要一起
Well, Raj and I always talked about learning
学怎么做这样的鸡尾酒 所以我自学完
how to make cocktails like this together, so I taught myself
把这照片发到Instagram上 让他看着
and I'm putting this on Instagram so he can see it
SB了吧 茄子
and feel like a turd. Say cheese.
是因为他研究宇宙探测仪却没带上你吗?
Is this about the space probe he's working on without you?
真聪明 猜中了
You betcha. The very one.
Howard 你是个成年人
Howard, you're grown men.
你们不必什么事都在一起做
You guys don't have to do everything together.
我知道 所以我今晚和你待在一起啊
I know. That's why I'm spending tonight with you.
就是为了让Raj不爽
Trying to hurt Raj's feelings.
和亲爱的在一起
With my honeybunch.
你这样很幼稚
You're being childish.
不 他才是
No. He is.
是啊我这个人比较有支配欲
So I have a dominant personality.
这点大家都知道
We all know that.
不好意思 大家都知道什么?
I'm sorry. What do we know?
在社交圈子里
In social groupings,
最后总是自然而然由我说了算
I just naturally wind up in charge.
别误会啊 但是我问你下
Don't take this the wrong way, but how many
这些酒珠你都喝了多少了?
of these little booze balls have you had?
你不觉得我是人群里的领导者吗?
You don't think I'm a leader?
我开玩笑的 你当然是啊
I was kidding. Of course you are.
对啊 想改也改不了
Right. I couldn't change if I wanted to.
你最好不要改变 因为我喜欢你现在的样子
You better not change, because I love who you are.
你喝完以后需不需要我帮忙把这收拾下
Now, will you need help cleaning all this up when you're done
还是你可以自己一个人全部做完?
or can you do it all by yourself?
我自己全部做完
All by myself.
真是我的好领导
There's my big boss man.
所以 在火车头的前面通常
So, often on the front of the locomotive
是一个铁制的楔子
is a large iron wedge
用来把轨道上的物体清除
for clearing objects off the tracks.
尽管大家普遍认为它是机车排障器
Now, while commonly known as a cowcatcher,
我更喜欢"排牛爆炸器"这种更精确的叫法
I prefer the more accurate "cow exploder"
好 Sheldon 我问你个问题
Okay. Sheldon, let me ask you a question.
嗯 如果我在一个火车站
Mmm. If I was at a train station
其中一辆火车通往我现在的工作
and one train could take me to my current job
而另一辆能带我去一部电影的面试
and the other train could take me to an audition for a movie,
我应该上哪辆车?
which train should I get on?
你是想用火车的梗骗我给你建议吧?
Are you using trains to trick me into giving you advice?
不是
No.
那 好吧
All right, then.
你应该坐上第三辆火车
You should take a third train
它能带你去试镜
where you audition for the movie
但是你可以晚一些再做职业上的抉择
but hold off on making a career decision
直到你有更多的信息为止
until you have more information.
哦 你说得对
Oh. You're right.
我在担心一些甚至还没发生的事情
I'm worried about something that hasn't even happened yet.
哈
Huh.
你真是个智者
You are a wise man.
嗯 Penny 哪个人更聪明：是那个智者
Well, Penny, who's smarter: the wise man
还是那个向他寻求建议的人?
or the person who comes to him for advice?
哦 我想你是对的
Oh, I guess you're right.
大概是那个求建议的人
Maybe it is the person who asks.
不 是那个智者
No, it's the wise man.
所以他才被称为智者
That's why he's called the wise man.
你知道我怎么知道的吗?
You know how I know that?
我就是智者啊
I'm the wise man.
不好意思 我刚刚在想什么?
I'm sorry. What was I thinking?
呃 只是好奇哈
Uh, just out of curiosity,
你为什么不问Leonard对这事的建议?
why didn't you ask Leonard for advice about this?
因为我都知道他会说啥
'Cause I already know what he'll say.
哇 哇 哇 你不该这么干
Wah, wah, wah, you shouldn't do it.
学得太像了!
It's just like he's here!
好的 所以我们了解到之前尝试
Okay, so we know that previous attempts
向太空中发送消息的方式 比如旅行者上的金唱片
to send a message into space, like the Golden Record
这类尝试受到了严厉的批判
on Voyager, were heavily criticized.
嗯 让外星人播放唱片
Well, aliens could only play the Golden Record
他们还得先造出个唱片机
if they figured out how to build a record player.
不过 说句实在的 E.T.造出了个电话
Eh. Although, to be fair, I watched E.T. build a telephone
用的是拼读玩具和一把雨伞
out of a Speak & Spell and an umbrella.
那家伙就像一个迷你棕色版的发明大王
Dude was like a little brown MacGyver.
如果E.T.是真的 你这话就更有用了
That would be more helpful if E.T. were real.
嗯 他快死的时候我的感情确实很真实
Well, my feelings were real when he was about to die.
天啊 他躺在桌上 浑身都靠板子维持着
My God, when he's on the table and they use the paddles on him.
他全身都白了
And he's all white.
他们把他放进袋子里拉上拉链
They zip him up in that bag.
Gertie哭个不停
And Gertie can't stop crying.
花也谢了
The flower dies.
行 我们说些别的吧
Okay, let's talk about something else.
好 好 所以这... 这听起来
All right, all right. So it... it sounds
似乎我们需要一种简便的沟通方式
like we need a way to communicate that's simple.
并且不需要造出其他机器
And doesn't require outside machinery
去接收它
to be built to access it.
还存在问题的是我们甚至不知道
It's also a problem because we don't even know
找到它的外星人有没有视觉
if the aliens who find this can see.
他们沟通的方式
I mean, they might communicate
可能和我们完全不一样
in a totally different way than us.
就像当我的小狗对我生气的时候
Like when my dog is mad at me,
她会用在我的拖鞋里尿尿这种方式表达
she tells me by peeing in my slippers.
那实际上是个很不错的例子
That's actually a valid example.
动物确实会通过气味传递信息
Animals do deliver messages through scent.
蜜蜂用跳舞的方式相互沟通
Bees talk to each other by dancing.
鲸鱼也有属于它们的歌声
Whales have their songs.
Penny有20多种翻白眼的方式
Penny has about 20 different ways of rolling her eyes
每一种意思都不一样的
that each mean something different.
好的 所以 听起来是这样的
Okay, so, what it sounds like is,
我们需要的是一种装置
what we want is a device
不仅通过视觉传递信息
that can deliver a message through not only sight,
还通过其他的感官
but other senses, as well.
任何一个探索太空的文明所必须具备的感官里
The most basic sense that any space-faring civilization
最基础的就是触觉
would have to possess is touch.
哦 哦 哦!
Ooh. Ooh, ooh!
我们可以造一个视频播放装置
We could make a video-playing device
它可以同时将信息转化成
that simultaneously translates the information
一种可接触的介质
into a tactile medium.
我们所需做的就是建一个3D的交流系统!
All we have to do is rig up a 3-D communication system!
我们... 我们完全可以做到!
We... we can totally do that!
我知道啊! 太棒了!
I know! This is great!
- 嗯 这还是什么?  - 什么?
Yeah, you know what else it is?--  What?
这完全就是Sheldon和Howard所说的
Exactly what Sheldon and Howard said.
嗯 谢谢你在我的拖鞋里尿尿
Well, thank you for peeing in my slippers.
# 它是老虎的眼睛 #
# It's the eye of the tiger #
# 它是蝙蝠的耳朵 #
# It's the ear of the bat #
# 它是鲶鱼的胡须 #
# It's the whiskers of the catfish #
# 还有海象... #
# And the walrus... #
等等 并不是说你的歌不糟糕... 是...
Hang on. Not that your song isn't terrible... it is...
但是你怎么能提到了蝙蝠却把声纳给忘了呢?
but how do you mention bats and leave out sonar?
你没让我唱完
You didn't let me finish.
# 至于蝙蝠呢 #
# And also regarding the bat #
# 它有声纳啊 #
# It has sonar #
嘿
Hey.
Hello.
听着
Look,
我知道你俩挺沮丧的 但我们已经讨论过了
I know you guys are upset, but we've talked about it,
我们认为这样会比较有利
and we think it'd be beneficial
就是你们能加入我们的项目
for you to be part of the project.
哇 哇 哇 Sheldon 你听到了吗?
Well, well, well, did you hear that, Sheldon?
不好意思 我刚刚在想什么韵
I'm sorry. I was trying to think of what rhymes
会和"非洲食蚁兽的鼻子"押上
with "nose of the aardvark."
我们需要你们
We want you
和我们一起做这个项目
back on the project with us.
哇 哇 哇 Howard 你听到了吗?
Well, well, well, did you hear that, Howard?
听着 我们得承认
Look, we admit it.
你俩想出的点子非常不错
The idea that you guys came up with was really good,
我们需要你们的帮助
and I'd love your help.
我想你要说出这话还挺不容易的
I suppose it couldn't have been easy for you to say that.
确实不容易 所以... 你们加入吗?
It wasn't, so... are you in?
- 当然  - 太好了
- Certainly. Sure.  - Great.
既然我们已经达成共识了
Now that we're all on the same page,
我们就今晚聚在一起开始着手做吧
let's get together tonight and work on it.
"今晚聚在一起"?
"Get together tonight"?
Leonard 你别什么事都要说了算
Leonard, stop trying to control everything,
给可怜的Raj一次机会让他想想我们该干啥
and give poor Raj a chance to come up with what we should do.
说吧 Raj
Go ahead, Raj.
好 我认为我应该现在就开始
Okay, I think we should do it right now.
今晚对我更合适
Tonight works better for me.
好
Okay.
好 就是个试镜而已
Okay, it's just an audition.
我为什么要紧张?
Why am I nervous?
可能是好事吧
Maybe it's a good thing.
代表我很想搞定它
Just means I want it.
而且我也可以搞定
And I can have it.
这种感觉太好了
This feels right.
我之前为什么要放弃?
Why did I ever give this up?
我大概想起来了
I'm starting to remember.
所以 我想尝试一种新的方式
So, I'd like to try a technique
没人会觉得自己被碾压
where no one gets steamrolled.
在你说话的时候
When you talk,
你并不是提出新的观点 而是就之前所说的话
instead of bringing up a new idea, respect what was
进行拓展和延伸
just said by building on it.
呃 说到这...
Uh, building on that...
我们该订外卖了
we should order dinner.
这和他刚刚说的有什么关系?
How is that building on what he just said?
既然Sheldon说到这里 我觉得我们可以吃中餐
Building on what Sheldon said, I could go for Chinese.
等等 就像Leonard说的那样
Hang on. Building on what Leonard said,
没人是在继续我的话题
no one built on what I said.
根据 "新的话题要延续之前的话题"这一条
Building on "building on that"
Colorado路上新开了一家自选披萨店
there's a new build-your-own pizza place on Colorado.
说到这里 我想提醒你一句
Building on that, I'd like to remind you,
我有乳糖不耐症
I'm lactose intolerant.
我看过菜单了 他们有豆奶干酪
I saw the menu. They have soy cheese.
哈哈! 你没有说"根据" 你输了!
Ha, ha! You didn't say "building on." You're out!
这又不是造句的游戏
It's not Simon Says.
- 是啊 Sheldon你的重点错了  - 你们俩都输了
- Yeah, you're missing the point, Sheldon.  - You're out, and you're out.
我赢了! 谁想吃披萨?
I win! Who wants pizza?
是你啊 Penny?
Penny?
- 哦 嗨  - 嗨
- Oh, hey.  - Hey.
好久没见你参加试镜了
I haven't seen you auditioning in a while.
是啊 我现在在一家药厂做销售代表
Yeah, uh, I got a job as a pharmaceutical sales rep.
- 你退出演艺圈了?  - 算是吧
- You quit acting?  - Well, kind of.
不过我现在可以信口雌黄
But now I get to act like
说心口灼热只算是"轻微的副作用"
inflamed heart is only a "mild side effect."
听说你现在的工作能挣不少钱
I heard you can make good money doing that.
是啊 确实还好 不过有时候我也挺怀念这种感觉的
Yeah, it's going okay, but I do miss this sometimes.
- 真的吗?  - 是啊
- Really?  - Mmm.
说实话 我都快吐了
Because I got to tell you, I am so sick
每天这样像市场里的猪肉一样被人挑肥拣瘦
of the humiliation and being treated like a piece of meat.
- Chelsea?  - 祝我好运吧
- Chelsea?  - Wish me luck.
他们会选中你的
They're gonna love you.
我听说她都快四十了 全靠整容才能继续演戏
I heard she's pushing 40 and everything's fake.
其实 这谣言是我造的
Yeah. I started that rumor.
好吧 既然我们已经就发送信息的系统
Okay, since we agree on the delivery system
达成了共识 我们是不是应该谈谈
for the message, maybe we should talk
到底应该发送什么信息
about what the message could be.
我觉得我们应该展示出地球生物的样子
Well, I think we should show what earthlings look like.
他们发射到太空的先驱者镀金铝板上有一幅画
The plaque they sent up on the Pioneer probe had a drawing
画上是躶体的男女
of a naked man and woman on it.
是嘛 我向来就不喜欢那个
Yeah, I never cared for that.
这简直就是在向外星捕食者
It's advertising to predator races
展示我们鲜嫩柔软的口感
just how soft and squishy we are.
捏你自己去!
Squeeze yourself!
我没有冒犯你的意思
Oh, don't be offended.
你也知道 我们四个里面
You know, of the four of us,
你的质感最像小牛肉了
you have the most veal-like consistency.
好吧 应该有办法能让我们显得既不那么有攻击性
Well, maybe there's a way to appear nonaggressive,
又能在必要的时候有能力保护自己
but also be able to protect ourselves if necessary.
比如微笑着 并且用一只手挥手致意
Like smiling and waving with one hand,
而另一只手拎着一颗老虎的脑袋之类的
but the other hand holding the severed head of a tiger.
你想向外星人发送
You want to send a passive-aggressive message
消极攻击的信息?
out into the universe?
这太扯了
That's ridiculous.
你说的消极攻击
Oh, you mean passive-aggressive
是把你和你老婆一起吃大都会酒球的照片
like posting pictures of you and your wife
发在网上 而你明明知道
eating cosmopolitan balls
那球是属于我的吗?
that you know belong in my mouth?
可能Howard所说的消极攻击指的是
Perhaps Howard meant passive-aggressive
你让我们一起帮你做这个项目
like asking our group to help on your project,
可是只选了Leonard和你一起做
and then only choosing Leonard.
对不起 我让你们不开心了
Look, I'm sorry I hurt your feelings,
可是你们确实有点太强势了
but you do have strong personalities
永远都是你们在做决定
and always end up taking over.
也不总是吧
It's not always.
我们去参加漫展
What about when we went to Comic-Con
打扮成赫特族人贾巴(星球大战中角色)的时候呢?
and dressed like Jabba the Hutt?
你当贾巴的脑袋 我就得当
You got to be Jabba's head, and I got to be
他的大肥屁股
his fat slug butt.
那次成果相当不错
We looked great.
你们还让别人坐在我身上
You let a guy sit on me.
他扮的是莉亚公主(星球大战中角色)
He was dressed as Princess Leia.
拍照很合适
It made a nice picture.
我的意思是 有时候Raj和我会觉得被无视了
I'm just saying, sometimes Raj and I feel pushed aside.
是啊 你开车带Sheldon去德州
Yeah. Like when you took Sheldon to Texas
参观NASA的那次...
and showed him all around NASA...
你连问都没问我和Leonard
you didn't even think to ask me and Leonard.
你说的有道理啊
You know what? You're right.
我应该问问你们的
I should have asked you.
是啊 如果他真的邀请你们的话 一定要去
Yeah, and if he does ask you, go.
那里棒呆了
It's amazing.
好吧 要是说起来
Okay, and if we're talking
被抛弃什么的
about being left out of things,
(星球大战导演George Lucas 的住处)
你们去天桥庄园的那次也没带我们啊
you guys went to Skywalker Ranch without us.
哦 那里也不错
Oh, I recommend that, too.
简直是传奇之旅!
That was a magical experience!
等等
Wait a minute.
(著名演员 星球大战黑武士配音演员)
有一次Sheldon和James Earl Jones待了一整天
Sheldon spent a whole day with James Earl Jones
我们谁都不知道
and never told any of us.
是啊是啊
I sure did.
天啊!
Oh, my goodness!
当了贾巴的头还和"黑武士"一起吃了冰激凌
Well, from Jabba's head to ice cream with Darth Vader,
我的人生简直精彩
I'm having a heck of a ride.
是啊 你们看
Yeah, look,
我做决定的时候
clearly, good things happen
总能有好事发生
when I'm in charge.
现在
Now, why don't
不如你们都让开 让我一个人搞定这个项目怎么样?
you boys step aside, let me knock this project out?
嘿 Sheldon
Sheldon,
这事不是你说了算
you're not in charge.
Raj说了算
Raj is in charge.
Leonard 到底是谁负责?
Leonard, who's really in charge?
是所谓负责的人 还是让他去负责的那个人?
The person in charge, or those who put him in charge?
他说得对
He's right.
仔细想想 我们都是负责的人
If you think about it, we're all in charge.
不是 真正负责的人应该是...
No, the guy in charge is in...
为什么你们就听不懂啊?!
Why is everyone so bad at these?!
这次的经历让我想起来了
I mean, the whole experience reminded me
我有多痛恨那种生活
about how much I hated about that world.
你们... 你们懂的 那种焦虑 抑郁 还有负面情绪
You... you know, the anxiety, the depression, the negativity.
我不想再去经历那种感受了
I don't want to feel those things.
我想把药卖给有这种感受的人吃
I want to sell drugs to people who feel those things.
真不敢相信你居然就这样起身离开了
I can't believe you got up and walked out
一部大片的试镜
of an audition for a big movie.
没错
I did.
其实我... 我还是进去了的 还试读了台词
I... I mean, I walked in, read for the part,
搞砸了整个试镜 然后就头也不回地走了
then stunk up the place, but then I walked right out.
我很高兴
Well, I'm glad
你对你的工作更上心了
you have a new appreciation for your job.
是啊 而且我好像
I do, and you know, I don't think
还没正式谢谢你 帮我找到了这么好的工作呢
I've ever thanked you properly for helping me get it.
正式不正式 有没有
Properly, at all.
反正我都没听过
It's just words I've never heard.
好吧 谢谢你啦
Well, thank you.
你是个称职的好朋友 你改变了我的生活
You're a good friend, and you changed my life.
不用谢
You're welcome.
既然你现在挣了不少钱了
Hey, now that you're making some real money,
是不是该请我这个帮过你的朋友吃顿好的啊
maybe you can take your friend out for a nice thank-you dinner.
没问题
Sure.
你大概也应该请你的另一个朋友一起去
And you probably have to invite your other friend
因为她已经听到你说要请人吃饭了
'cause she overheard you talking about it,
不请她的话 她会觉得尴尬的
and it would be awkward to exclude her.
好吧
Okay.
现在就走吧?
How about now?
听你的
All right.
别忘带钱包
Don't forget your wallet.
我...
I...
请接收来自地球的问候
Greetings from planet Earth.
在半人马阿尔法行星处左拐
Just turn left at Alpha Centauri.
一定能找到我们的
You can't miss it.
这个软萌粉的外星人看起来好像很好吃的样子
我可以吃掉他